Preliminary Guide to the Charles H. Johnson Papers
Department of Special Collections
Charles H. Johnson Papers,
ca. 1858-1916
(bulk 1861-1866)
Wyles Mss 36
Johnson (Charles F.)
.4 linear feet (1 document box)
University of California, Santa Barbara. Library. Department of Special Collections Santa Barbara, California 93106-9010
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1977.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection mainly contains correspondence from Charles H. Johnson, a Civil War Union soldier, Michigan Cavalry, 1st Regiment (Vol), Co. M, to his mother, 1858-1866, as well as some later correspondence, a few photographs, and miscellany, including a cookbook with medicinal recipes and Civil War diary entries from 1862.
Collection Contents
- 1858-1860, 1858 - 1860 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Correspondence (mainly to his mother) (Box-folder 1: 1 - 9)
- 1861, 1861 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- 1862, 1862 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- 1863, 1863 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- 1864, 1864 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- 1865, 1865 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- 1866, 1866 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- 1868-1898, 1868 - 1898 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- 1904, n.d., n.d. (Box-folder 1: 9)
- Photographs (3 items, incl. 1 tintype, apparently of Johnson), n.d. (Box-folder 1: 10)
- Miscellany, ca. 1862 - 1916, [Incl. marriage and death records, clippings, sewing kit, and cookbook [connection to Johnson unknown], which also contains medicinal recipes and 1862 Civil War diary entries] (Box-folder 1: 11)